There.
那里
Technicals, nine o'clock.
九点钟方向有武装车
Oh, shit! Did you see that?
该死 你看到吗?
Chief, we got unarmed civilians getting shot down here at nine o'clock.
九点钟方向有平民遭到攻击
I got it, Matt. I don't think we can touch this.
收到了 但我们不能干涉
This food is the property of Mohamed Farrah Aidid!
这些粮食属于艾迪德
Go back to your homes!
快滚回家吧
Command, Super 64...
这是超级64号
... we got militia shooting civilians at the food distribution center.
民兵在粮食分发中心扫射平民
Request permission to engage.
请准许攻击
Super 64, are you taking fire? Over.
你遭到炮火攻击吗?
Negative, command.
没有
U.N.'s jurisdiction, 64. We cannot intervene.
这是联合国辖区 我们不能干涉
- Return to base. Over. - Roger.
返回基地 收到
64 returning.
64号返回基地
Ready, Mr. Atto.
可以走了 奥图先生
Leaving.
他要走了
Sir.
先生
Keep Driving!
继续开
I'm going to be late.
我会迟到
Call you back.
待会再打给你
General Garrison?
盖瑞森将军
No, thanks. I got one.
谢了 我有了
But these are Cuban.
这是古巴雪茄
Bolivar Belicoso.
上好的雪茄
So is this.
这也是
Miami, my friend, is not Cuba.
迈阿密雪茄没古巴雪茄赞
I see not catching Aidid is becoming a routine.
你们老是抓不到艾迪德
We weren't trying to catch Aidid. We were trying to catch you.
这次我们要抓的是你
Me?
我?
But am I that important?
我有这么重要吗?
I hardly think so.
没有吧
- You're just a businessman. - Trying to make a living.
你只是个生意人 只想混口饭吃
Yeah. Selling guns to Aidid's militia.
你贩卖枪械给艾迪德的民兵
You've been here, what?
你来了多久?
Six weeks?
6个星期?
Six weeks you are trying to catch the general.
6星期来你一直想抓到他
You put up reward posters.
到处张帖悬赏海报
$25,000. What is this? Gunfight at the K.O. Corral?
两万五千美元 你想演"终结追杀令"吗?
It's the O.K. Corral.
是"绝命追杀令"
Do you think bringing me in will make him suddenly come to you?
你以为把我抓来他就会自首?
Make him more agreeable?
乖乖束手就擒?
You know where he sleeps.
你知道他在哪里
You pay for his beds, much less his militia.
你资助他的一切 包括民兵
We're not leaving Somalia till we find him.
我们逮不到他就不走
And we will find him.
我们一定会逮到他
Don't think because I grew up without running water...
别以为我从小没自来水喝
...I am simple, General.
就是个笨蛋
I do know something about history.
我对历史很了解
See all this? It's simply shaping tomorrow.
你看到吗?     我们在创造明天
A tomorrow without a lot of Arkansas white boys' ideas in it.
一个没有阿肯色州白小子的明天
Well, I wouldn't know about that. I'm from Texas.
我来自德州
Mr. Garrison, I think you shouldn't have come here.
盖将军 你们不该来这儿
This is civil war.
这是内战
This is our war.
这是我们的战争
Not yours.
不是你们的
300,000 dead and counting.
三十万人死亡
That's not a war, Mr. Atto. That's genocide.
这不是战争 这是种族屠杀
Now, you enjoy that tea, you hear?
喝茶吧
How'd he strike you?
你觉得他怎样?
Urbane, sophisticated, cruel.
彬彬有礼 冷酷无情
Yeah, he's a good catch.
他是一条大鱼
It'll take time, but Aidid will feel the loss.
时间一久艾迪德就会感到受制
I'm not sure time is something we got in great supply.
我们没有太多时间
This isn't Iraq, you know. Much more complicated than that.
这比伊拉克的情形更复杂
Boss, most of Washington might disagree.
但华府官员可不这么想
They've been calling for situation reports every morning this week.
他们每天都要我们提出报告
Well, tell them the situation is fragile.
你就说战争一触即发
Ladies and gentlemen, I'm Cliff "Elvis" Wolcott.
各位 我是猫王威考
I'll be your pilot today.
本班机的机长
Federal regulations designate this a non-smoking Black Hawk helicopter.
这架黑鹰直升机是非吸烟区
Those in Mogadishu frequent flyer program will earn 100 free credits.
本航空公司的会员 可以累积100点的哩程
And as always, the air sickness bags are in the seatback in front of you.
呕吐袋就放在前座的椅背
Number one indications are good, Cliff. Put her on two.
一号引擎正常 检查二号引擎
You're still clear.
没问题
61, this is 64. Go to UHF secure.
这是64号 使用高频无线电
I've got some bad news.
我有坏消息
"Limo" is a word, Durant. I don't want to hear about it.
礼车是一个字 别跟我罗唆
It is not a word. It's an abbreviation of a word.
那是缩写 不是一个字
"Limo" is a word in common usage.
那是常用语
That is the key phrase in Scrabble, my good friend. Common usage.
拼字游戏的规则接受常用语
If it's not in the dictionary it doesn't count!
字典查不到就不算
It doesn't have to be in the dictionary!
字典查不到也算
When we get back to the base, it's coming off.
等我回基地就把这个字剔除
You touch my "limo" and I'll spank you, Nightstalker.
你敢我就扁你 听到吗?
Yeah, promises.
你有种扁我才怪
That's a nice beach down there.
好美的海滩
How's the water?
海水怎样?
Yeah, it's nice and warm. And it's loaded with sharks.
很暖和 到处都是鲨鱼
- Name. - Todd.
名字 陶德
- Last name. - Blackburn.
姓氏 贝克朋
First name, Todd.
名字是陶德
- So, what's it like? - What's what like?
怎样? 什么怎样?
Mogadishu. The fighting.
摩加迪休 战事
- Serial number. - 72163427.
兵籍号码
Firstly, it's "the Mog" or simply "Mog." No one calls it Mogadishu here.
大家都简称为摩加 不会说摩加迪休
Secondly, I wouldn't know about the fighting, so don't ask.
我没有打仗 别问我
Why not?
为什么?
Didn't I just say, "Don't ask"?
我叫你别问我
You look like you're about 12, so let me explain something to you.
你像个小孩 我解释给你听
I have a rare and mysterious skill that precludes me from doing missions.
我有一种特殊才能 不必打仗
Typing.
打字
- Can you type? - No.
你会吗? 不会
- Date of birth. - 2-27-75.
生日 1975年2月27日
Well, I'm here to kick some ass.
我是来踢爆坏人的
Let's bring it in.
回去吧
Nice, man! Very smooth!
漂亮 干得好
Single shot through the engine block.
一枪就射穿引擎
Shit, that's a shame. That was a nice jeep.
真可惜 那辆吉普车很帅
Cease fire! Cease fire!
停火
Check your weapons!
检查武器
Sergeant Eversmann.
艾中士
Private First Class Blackburn.
我是一等兵贝克朋
Yeah?
什么事?
Reporting for duty.
我来报到
Not to me. You're reporting to It. Beales. He should be here somewhere.
你要向毕中尉报到 他应该就在附近
Can I leave him with you?
我把他交给你
Yeah, go ahead.
好吧
- You brought your weapon. - Yes, sir.
你把枪带来了 是 长官
Want me to shoot? I'm rested.
我不累 我能练靶吗?
- When did you get in? - Just now, Sergeant.
你几时到? 刚才
Hey, who's hungry?
谁饿了?
What is this, Sarg'nt? Another taxpayer-funded Delta safari?
这算什么? 纳税人出钱的狩猎大餐吗?
- Not if General Garrison is asking. - I'm asking.
盖将军问起可别说 我问起呢?
Have a nice meal, Captain.
用餐愉快 上尉
- Hey, man, there's a line. - I know.
大家都在排队 我知道
- Well, this isn't the back of it. - Yeah, I know.
你这是插队 我也知道
Sergeant. Sergeant.
中士
What's going on here?
这干嘛?
Some aerial target practice, sir. Didn't want to leave it behind.
我们在练靶 打到一只野猪
I'm talking about your weapon.
我是说你的步枪
Delta or no Delta, that's a hot weapon.
反恐怖部队也不能 拿上膛的步枪到处晃
You know better than that. Safety should be on at all times on base.
你应该很清楚 枪要随时上保险
Well, this is my safety, sir.
这就是我的"保险"
Let it go, sir. The guy hasn't eaten in a couple of days.
别管他 他两天没吃饭了
You Delta boys are a bunch of undisciplined cowboys.
反恐怖部队都是一群蛮牛
Let me tell you something, Sarg'nt.
让我告诉你
When we get on a five-yard line, you're going to need my Rangers.
到了前线你需要游骑兵支援
Y'all better learn to be team players.
你最好有点团队精神
We're done here.
我说完了
Speak up. You say this is your safety?
说呀 你说这是保险
Well, this is my boot, son.
这是我的靴子
And it will fit up your ass with the proper amount of force.
小心我用这只靴子把你踢爆
- Is that a Jersey accent? - I'm trying to do this, give me a break.
这算新泽西口音吗? 拜托 我很努力耶
Take those sunglasses off.
把太阳眼镜脱掉
Delta wants to wear Oakleys, that's their business.
反恐怖部队爱戴名牌墨镜 那是他们的事
I don't want to see them on you again.
别让我再看到你戴
Is that a hot weapon?
那是一把上膛的步枪?
Is that your move?
你下了吗?
Is my hand on the piece?
手还没离棋啊?
I can mate you in three whatever you do.
再下三步我就赢了
I'd keep my eye on that queen before counseling others.
你自己最好小心点
Well, she's just lying in wait.
有种就放马过来
Yikes.
唉
It's good. You're really improving.
你画得越来越好了
If I may make a suggestion... Observation.
不过我有一个建议
Go ahead.
说吧
- It's a children's book, right? - Right.
这是童话故事 对吧? 没错
They are not supposed to scare the living shit out of the children.
这会把小孩子吓得屁滚尿流
This is the part of the story where our knight is slaying the dragon.
骑士正要屠龙
That's scary. Besides, my daughter loves this stuff.
本来就很可怕 而且我女儿最喜欢了
Thought you finished that last week.
我以为你上礼拜就画完了
You done?
你说完了吗?
Hey, we are at the 10-yard line here, men.
就快冲到十码线了
You understand?
明白吗?
Can you count? One, two, ten.
你会数吗?1 2 3
Okay? Where are my running backs?
我的后卫呢?
Hey, I didn't see you at church on Sunday.
我没看到你做礼拜
You had something more important to do?
你有别的事吗?
Not on Sunday, you don't. Not anymore.
礼拜天一定要做礼拜
I will make you believe, you understand?
别给我落跑 了解吗?
Pretty funny, hoo-ah?
很好笑 呼吓
It was a good impression. I recognize myself.
你学得很像 很像我
All right, carry on.
继续吧
- I'd like a word, specialist. - Sir.
我要跟你讲话 是 长官
You understand why we have a chain of command, don't you?
你知道谁有指挥权吧?
Roger that, sir.
知道 长官
If you ever undermine me again, you'll clean latrines with your tongue...
你敢再取笑我 我就命令你把马桶舔干净
...till you taste no difference between shit and French fries.
保证你一个月吃不下饭
- Are we clear? - Hoo-ah, sir.
明白吗? 明白 长官
All right.
好吧
Listen to this:
听好:
If one skinny kills another his clan owes the dead guy's clan a hundred camels.
当一个索马利亚人杀了人 他的部落就欠对方部落一百只骆驼
A hundred camels.
一百只骆驼
Camels. I wouldn't pay one camel.
我连一只都不给
Must be a lot of fucking camel debt.
这儿的骆驼欠债一定很多
Is that really true, Lieutenant?
这是真的吗?
Ask Sgt. Eversmann. He likes skinnies.
去问艾士官 他喜欢非洲人
Sgt. Eversmann, you really like the skinnies?
艾士官 那是真的吗?
It's not that I like them or I don't like them. I respect them.
不是喜欢不喜欢的问题 我尊敬他们
See, what you guys fail to realize is the sergeant is a bit of an idealist.
你们要知道艾士官很有理想
He believes in this mission down to his bones. Don't you, Sergeant?
他相信这项任务的使命 对吧 士官?
Look, these people, they have no jobs...
这些人没有工作
...no food, no education, no future.
没有食物 教育和未来
I just figure that, I mean, we have two things that we can do.
我只是觉得我们有两个选择
We can help...
帮助他们
...or we can sit back and watch the country destroy itself on CNN.
或是眼睁睁看着他们自相残杀
Right?
对吧?
I don't know about you guys, but I was trained to fight.
我不知道 我是来打仗的
Are you trained to fight, Sergeant?
你不是吗?
Well, I think I was trained to make a difference, Kurth.
我是来改善世界的
Like the man said, he's an idealist.
他真的很有理想
Oh, wait. This is my favorite part.
等等 我最爱这一段
Stay away from the cans!
滚远一点
Die, gas-pumper!
去死吧 猪头
Stay away from those cans!
给我滚远一点
No, no, stay back.
不 退后
He's having a seizure. Put something in his mouth.
他的癫痫症发作了 拿东西让他咬着
John, it's okay. John, it's okay. It's okay.
约翰 没事了…没事了…
Well, he'll be fine. But not in this army.
他没事了 不过他得退伍
He's out of the game. He's epileptic, going home.
他有癫痫症 我要送他回家
I'm putting you in charge of his chalk.
我要你当小队长
- You got a problem with that? - No, sir.
你有意见吗? 没有 长官
It's a big responsibility.
这个责任很重大
Your men will look to you to make the right decisions.
你的弟兄都仰赖你
Their lives depend on it.
他们的命都在你手上
All right.
好了
- Rangers lead the way, sir. - All the way.
游骑兵做先锋 勇往直前
Good luck.
祝好运
A meeting of Aidid's senior cabinet may take place today at 1500 hours.
艾迪德的资深阁员 今天下午三点可能要开会
I say "may" because we all know by now...
我说可能是因为...
...with the intel we get on the street, nothing is certain.
根据目前的情报 一切都不确定
This is actual intel confirmed by three sources.
这是三方确定的情报
Two tier-one personalities may be present:
两名高层阁员可能会在场
Omar Salad, Aidid's top political advisor...
奥玛萨拉 艾迪德的政治顾问
...and Abdi Hassan Awale, interior minister.
哈珊奥威利 内政部长
These are the guys we're after.
他们是我们的目标
Today we go.
今天就行动
Same mission template as before.
任务计划和以前一样
1545, Assault Force Delta will infiltrate the target building...
3点45分 反恐怖部队攻击小组 负责攻入敌方建筑物
...and seize all suspects within.
逮捕内部所有嫌疑犯
Security Force Rangers: 4 Ranger chalks, under command of Capt. Steele...
史上尉指挥的游骑兵小队
...will rope in at 1546...
要在3点46分
...and hold a four-corner perimeter around the target building.
在目标的四个角落建立防线
No one gets in or out.
任何人不得进出
Extraction Force:
撤退部队
It. Colonel McKnight's humvee column will drive in at 1547...
麦奈中校的悍马车队 在3点47分开进哈瓦迪街
...on Hawlwadig Road and hold just short of the Olympic Hotel.
停在奥林匹克旅馆前
Wait for the green light.
等待指令
Now once Delta gives the word...
当反恐怖部队突击成功
...McKnight's column will go to the target and load the prisoners onto trucks.
麦中校的手下就把人犯架上车
Immediately after the prisoners are loaded...
把人犯架上车后
...the four Ranger chalks will collapse back to the target building...
游骑兵队员立刻到目标大楼集合
...load up on humvees...
一起上悍马车队
...and the entire ground force will exfil the 3 miles back to base.
地面部队就一路赶回基地
Mission time, no longer than 30 minutes.
行动时间只有半小时
Now, I had requested light armor and AC-130 Spectre gunships...
我请求调动装甲车 和AC-130炮艇机支援
...but Washington, in all its wisdom, decided against this.
但华府却不同意
Too high-profile.
太显眼了
So Black Hawks and Little Birds will provide the air cover...
准备多管机枪的 黑鹰直升机
...with miniguns and 2.75 rockets.
将提供空中支援
Colonel Harrell.
哈上校
In the C-2 bird, Colonel Matthews will coordinate the air mission...
马上校负责调派空中支援
...and I will coordinate ground forces.
我负责指挥地面部队
Colonel Matthews.
马上校
Mission launch code word is Irene.
任务执行代号是艾琳
Questions?
有问题吗?
Which building is it, sir?
目标是哪栋建筑?
We're confirming that now. Somewhere near the Bakara market.
巴卡拉市集附近的建筑物
I don't choose the time or place of their meetings.
我不能决定他们在哪里开会
I didn't say a word, sir.
我没这么说
Make no mistake, once you're in the Bakara market...
大家听好 你们到了市集
...you're in an entirely hostile district.
就等于进入敌区
Don't underestimate their capabilities.
千万别低估敌人实力
We'll be in friendly neighborhoods before we hit the market...
进入市集之前都不是敌区
...so remember the rules of engagement: No one fires unless fired upon.
千万切记交战法则 遭到攻击才能反击
Now, let's go get this thing done.
完成任务吧
Good luck, gentlemen.
祝好运 各位
What's the matter, Danny? Something you don't like?
怎么了?你不满意吗?
No Spectre gunships, daylight instead of night...
没有C－炮艇机 白天出任务
...afternoon when they're all fucked up on khat...
敌人的精神在下午特别亢奋
...only part of the city Aidid can mount a counter-attack on short notice...
那儿又是火力集中的敌区
- What's not to like? - Life's imperfect.
我有什么不满意的? 人生不如意十有八九
For you two, circling above it at 500 feet, it's imperfect.
你们在半空中只是不如意
Down in the street, it's unforgiving.
我们在地面就苦不堪言
What the fuck, Smith?
搞什么?
- Well? - Well, what?
怎样? 什么怎样?
We going?
我们要行动吗?
- Why should I tell you that? - Because I'm me.
我干嘛告诉你 你就是要说
Yeah. 3:00. Downtown.
对 下午三点 市中心
- Bakara market. - All right.
巴卡拉市集 好耶
Listen, Smith, I need you to back me up out there today, all right?
小史 我要你全力支持我
Keep sharp.
提高警觉
Yes, sir, Sergeant Eversmann.
遵命 艾士官
Ev, it's going to be nothing, man.
这次行动是小意思啦
Nothing.
小意思
It's all in the grind, Sizemore. Can't be too fine, can't be too coarse.
关键是磨咖啡豆 不能磨得太细或太粗
This, my friend, is a science.
这是一种技巧
You're looking at the guy that believed the commercials.
我可是相信徵兵广告的那种人
About "be all you can be."
尽忠报国
I made coffee through Desert Storm.
但是我在波湾战争都在煮咖啡
I made coffee through Panama, while everyone else got to fight...
在巴拿马也煮咖啡 别的游骑兵队员
...got to be a Ranger.
都出生入死
Now it's "Grimesy, black, one sugar" or "Grimesy, got a powdered anywhere?"
我却只能煮黑咖啡 替别人拿奶精
- What happened to you? - Ping-Pong accident.
怎么了? 乒乓球受伤
What?
什么?
So guess what.
猜怎么着?
Your wish has been granted. You're going out today.
你的愿望实现了 你要出任务
You're fucking me.
少唬烂我
You're taking my place assisting the 60 gunner.
你要代替我负责 有装备枪榴弹的M－步枪
Sergeant Eversmann said to get your stuff and get ready.
艾士官叫你收拾好装备
It's what you wanted, isn't it?
你想要打仗 不是吗?
Oh, yeah.
是啊
Hell, yeah.
当然了
Grimesy, stick with Waddell and give him ammo when he needs it.
葛姆 跟着瓦德给他弹药
- Hoo-ah? - Hoo-ah.
呼吓? 呼吓
I wouldn't worry about that. Generally speaking, Somalis can't shoot for shit.
别担心 索利亚人的枪法都很烂
Just watch out for the sammys throwing the rocks, and you'll be fine.
小心别被他们的石头K到就行
Might even be fun.
会好玩的
D-boys do their thing now. All we got to do is cover them.
让反恐怖部队打头阵 我们只要支援他们
Choppers going to cover us, and we'll be all right.
直升机也会掩护我们
Look, you guys, this is my first time as chalk leader...
我知道我是第一次当小队长
...but, this isn't our first time out together. This is serious.
但我们不是第一次出任务
We're Rangers, not some sorry-ass JROTC.
我们是游骑兵 不是预备军官
We're elite.
我们是精英部队
Let's act like it out there. Hoo-ah?
大家要好好表现
Any questions?
有问题吗?
We're going to be okay.
我们不会有事的
Grab your gear. Let's move out.
收拾好装备 出动吧
You're not going to need that, dude. We're not out there long enough.
你不需要水壶 很快就会回来
You won't need that, either.
那也用不着
We'll be back before dark.
天黑前就会回来
You might as well take dope and beer instead.
你不如多带大麻和啤酒
What?
什么?
Ammo, dude. Take ammo.
弹药啦 多带弹药啦
Let me tell you something, Grimes. You got 50 pounds of gear.
你身上有五十磅的装备
You don't need another 12.
不必多加十二磅
I don't know about you, I don't plan on getting shot running away.
背这么重想逃命都逃不了
Well, I better keep mine in.
我还是要穿防弹背心
Grimes.
葛姆
Most important thing:
最重要的是
Remember, when everyone is shooting, shoot in the same direction.
跟着大家射击的方向开枪
Look at this. He's taping his blood type to his boots.
你看 他在靴子帖上血型
- That's bad luck. - No, it's smart.
触霉头 很聪明
All Delta do that.
反恐怖部队都这么做
That's bad luck too, man.
写遗书也很倒霉
Come on, let's go.
快走吧
It's a good thing you're right-handed, Adonis.
幸好你不是左撇子
- If not, I don't know what you'd do. - You're a funny guy, man.
要不然你就没搞头了 你真会说笑
- I'm not taking no death letter. - We have a deal.
我不替你拿遗书 我们说好的
I'll give it to you back in an hour.
一小时后还给你
- Blackburn, you okay? - Excited.
贝克朋 你还好吧? 我很兴奋
In a good way. I've been training my whole life for this.
这是好事我当兵就是为了打仗
You ever shot at anybody before?
你杀过人吗?
No, sir.
没有
Me neither.
我也没有
Think he's reliable?
他可靠吗?
Well, we'll see. It's his first time out.
等着瞧吧 他第一次出任务
- Tell him to turn his damn radio off. - Yes, sir.
叫他把收音机关掉 是 长官
Tell him to turn his radio off.
叫他把收音机关掉
Abdi, you need to turn your radio off.
阿弟 把收音机关掉
Hi. You've reached Stephanie and Randy, leave us a message. Thank you.
这是史黛芬和蓝迪 请留言 谢谢
Hey, baby, it's me. Are you there?
老婆 是我 你在吗?
Pick up if you're there.
你在的话就快接
I'm just calling to make sure everything's all right.
我只是打来看你好不好
I'll call you in a couple hours.
过两小时再打给你
You'd better not be sleeping.
你最好别睡着了
Your move, Randy.
该你了 蓝迪
I'm missing you.
我好想你
I love you, baby.
我爱你
Hello? Hello?
喂?
Thanks, bud.
谢了
You know, it's kind of funny.
这有点好笑
Beautiful beach, beautiful sun.
洁白的沙滩 灿烂的阳光
Could almost be a good place to visit.
几乎是一个好地方
Almost.
几乎
You don't think we should be here.
你认为我们不该来
You know what I think? It don't really matter what I think.
你知道我怎么想吗? 我怎么想不重要
Once that first bullet goes past your head, politics and all that shit...
第一颗子弹从你头上呼啸而过
...just goes right out the window.
那些狗屁倒灶的事都不重要
I just want to do it right today.
我只想完成任务
Just watch your corner. Get all your men back here alive.
打起精神 让弟兄活着回来
Now, is this supposed to be the place, or did his car just take a dump?
就是这里还是汽车抛锚?
Abdi, come in.
阿弟 请回答
Abdi, can you hear me? Is this the place?
你听到吗?这是目标吗?
Can you hear me? Abdi.
听到吗?
Abdi, come in. Is this the place?
请回答 是这里吗?
To my right side, above the cafe.
我右手边 咖啡厅楼上
He says this is the building.
他说就是这里
He's certain?
他确定?
Abdi, you need to be sure.
阿弟 你要确定才行
Are you sure?
你确定?
Well, it's down the road, two blocks over on my left.
目标在我左边两条街口外
But there's too many militia.
不过民兵太多了
If I go closer, they might shoot me.
我一靠近他们就会开枪
Now he's saying the building's a couple blocks down...
他说目标在两个街口外
...but if he's seen outside it, he'll be shot.
不过他怕对方会向他开枪
I'll fucking shoot him myself.
我才会宰了他
Tell him I want his skinny ass parked in front of the building.
叫他把车子停在目标门口
He's not getting paid till he does exactly that.
他不去就拿不到钱
Three miles to the target. We're never off the main roads.
离目标三哩 不要走小路
At K-four traffic circle, we turn north, then east on National...
到了圆环先向北然后往东
...and we wait until extraction of prisoners is complete here.
在那儿等候劫出人犯
Then we roll up in force on Hawlwadig...
然后全队开进
...load the prisoners, the assault-blocking forces and bring them back.
把人犯跟地面部队载回来
Home in an hour. Okay?
一小时后回基地
There will be some shooting. Bakara market is the Wild West.
敌人会反击 那儿就像西部电影一样
But be careful what you shoot at. People do live there.
小心开枪 那儿有平民
Hoo-ah.
呼吓
Last one of these guys shot himself in the head playing Russian roulette.
上一个线民玩俄罗斯轮盘搁屁了
Sir, the vehicle is stopped.
长官 他停车了
So this is the real deal now. He's sure this time.
这就是目标 他确定吗?
- He sounds scared shitless. - Good. That's always a good sign.
他吓得屁滚尿流 好 好现象
That's it. That's our signal.
这就是我们的信号
All right.
好
All QRF out of the airspace.
要所有飞机离开该空域
All units, Irene. I say again, Irene.
全体注意 艾琳 重覆 艾琳
Check in when ready. Barber 51 up and ready. Star 41 up and ready.
检查完毕 B51号好了 S41号好了
Irene!
艾琳!
Copy, Irene.
收到
Fucking Irene!
出动了
Good luck, boys.
祝好运
Be careful.
小心点
No one gets left behind.
决不抛弃同胞
What's wrong?
怎么了?
Nothing. He's just never done that before.
他从没来道过别
Aw, fuck!
天杀的
Let's go.
走吧
Sergeant Struecker. Let's roll.
指崔克中士 出发吧
Two minutes.
两分钟
Why are they burning tires?
他们干嘛烧轮胎?
Signals to the militia that we're coming!
通知民兵我们要来了
Okay, 56, looks like there's some friendlies on the ground.
看来地面有平民
Looks like I've got a tally on the voice.
我能拦截到他们的对话
One minute.
一分钟
What's that for?
你在干嘛?
Last rope, I almost bit my tongue off.
上次我差点把舌头咬断
Touching base.
准备降落
Two feet, one foot...
两英尺 一英尺
... clear.
触地
Little birds touching down at target.
小型直升机安全降落
Ropes!
潘下绳索
Go! Go! Go!
快... 快...
Chalk One troops are on the deck. Chalk Two deployed.
第一小队着地 第二小队出动
This is McKnight. Uniform 64 approaching staging area.
这是麦奈 地面车队接近目标
Down! Get down!
趴下来!趴下!
Down! Stay down!
趴下!趴下!
Get down! Everybody down!
快趴下!
You, down!
你 趴下!
Get down!
趴下!
Let's go, let's go!
快走 走!
Grimesy! No fear!
葛姆 别害怕!
Oh, yeah, right!
是呀
Rangers securing perimeter. Four corners.
游骑兵守住防线
Colonel, they're shooting at us!
中校 他们在开火
Well, shoot back!
那就打回去啊
This is 64. Chalks on the ground, going into holding pattern.
我们到地面 准备建立防线
This is 62, delivered chalks. Going to cover pattern.
出动部队 准备建立防线
Super 62, take up an overhead pattern to provide sniper cover. Over.
黑鹰直升机 请在空中掩护
This is Super 65. Chalks on the ground, going into holding pattern.
部队登陆 准备建立防线
Go, Blackburn, go! Go!
贝克朋 快下去
Go, Blackburn!
快呀
RPG!
RPG火箭弹
Hold on!
抓紧了!
No!
不!
C- 2, we got a man fallen.
C-2 有位弟兄摔下去
Super-61, you're a sitting duck.
超级61号 别一直盘旋
Take up overhead pattern to provide sniper cover. Over.
请在空中掩护我们
Roger that. 61 coming out.
收到 我们要离开
13, go ahead. I need you to move to the north of the street.
13组 快赶到街口北边
Right to the north. Right there. Over.
那儿 就在那边
Doc! Doc Schmid!
史医官 快点
Come on!
快!
Schmid, we got a man hit.
史医官 有人受伤
- Where's he hit? - He's not. He fell.
哪里中弹? 没有 他摔下来
- What? - He fell.
什么? 他摔下来
Why aren't you shooting?
你怎么不开枪?
We're not being shot at yet!
他们没向我们开枪
How can you tell?
你怎么分辨?
A hiss means it's close.
子弹咻一声代表很近
A snap means...
啪哒一声表示...
Now they're shooting at us!
他们向我们开枪了
Galentine!
杰利顿!
Get me Captain Steele! Get me Captain Steele!
快帮我接史上尉!
Juliet 64, this is Juliet 25. Come in. Over.
J64 这是J25 请回答
Blackburn, can you hear me?
贝克朋 听得到吗?
Juliet 64, this is 25. Come in. Over.
J64 这是25 请回答
I can't get him!
我联络不到他
Juliet 64, this is Chalk Four! We've got a man down!
J64 这是第四小队! 有弟兄受伤!
We need to get him out of here! Over.
快把他救走!
This is 64. Say again, 25. Over.
请再说一次
We've got a man down! Over.
有一名弟兄受伤
Take a breath, 25, and calm down. Over.
别紧张 冷静点
- Man down! - Missed that, 25.
弟兄受伤 没听到
- Fuck it. - Say again.
没用 再说一次
Matt, it's a long way to the humvees!
我们离悍马车队很远
We'll get a stretcher in here. Get him to the target building.
这儿有担架 把他抬进去
What did he say?
他说什么?
Super 61, we got a man wounded on the ground.
有一名弟兄受伤倒地
- Stretcher! - Get me a stretcher!
担架  快拿担架
Come on. Stretcher.
快点
Come on, come on!
快点…
Grab this end!
抓住另一边
Let's go!
走吧
- All right. - Go.
好 走
Get him to the humvees. We'll hold down the corner.
把他抬上悍马车 我们来掩护
Up to the humvees! Now!
快把他抬上车
Go! Go!
快 快
Keep moving, Grimes! Run!
快走 快跑
- Secure! - Let's move out!
安全 走吧
Everybody up! Let's go!
快起来 快走
Come on!
走吧
Let's go! Let's move!
快走
- Grimes, run! - All right.
葛姆 跑! 好啦
C- 2, this is Super 61, beginning my orbit of the target area.
C-2 这是超级61号 开始盘旋
Chalk Four, clear for a clear. Coming in.
第四小队 我们快要降落
Kilo 11, this is 61, providing cover for prisoner extract. Over.
凯罗11号 这是超级61号  我掩护你们
Kilo 64, green light.
可以行动
- Ready for extraction. Over. - Roger that. Will relay.
准备搭载人犯 收到了
That's it. We got them.
很好 逮到他们了
Uniform 64, ready for extraction. Over.
准备接收人犯
Roger that. There's the call. Let's move out!
收到了 他们下令了 快去吧
- Let's move out! - Hold on.
快去吧! 抓紧了
- How much longer? - Five minutes, sir.
还要多久? 五分钟
- What? - Five minutes.
什么? 五分钟
Nothing takes five minutes!
绝对不只五分钟
What happened to him?
他是怎么了?
- He fell! Missed the rope! - How'd he do that?
他没抓到绳索摔下去 怎么会?
Put him in that humvee! Grimes, give him a hand!
把他抬上车 帮帮忙
Let's go! Let's move it!
走吧 快走
Move, move! Come on! Move!
快 动作快点
Get him in there!
把他抬上去
Get ready to move!
快走
Go! Everybody move! Move!
快呀
Get the fuck up!
快上车
Grimes! Come on!
葛姆 来呀
Grimes! Grimes!
葛姆 葛姆
Fuck this!
我靠!
Fuck!
可恶
Let's go.
快走
Come on!
快点
Romeo 64, I need to send out three humvees with a casualty.
我要三辆悍马车后送伤兵
He looks real bad. I need to evac now.
他的伤势很重 必须立刻后送
Roger that, Uniform 64.
收到了
We'll chop a team of gun ships to you. Over.
我会派一组直升机去掩护你
Roger that.
收到
I need extra security on these humvees!
我要派人掩护悍马车队
I'll go. I'll take my team, make sure they get back okay.
我去 我带手下去掩护他们
Do it.
快去
Struecker, you're lead humvee.
史崔克 你带领车队
First three vehicles mount up, we're moving back to base.
快上车 我们要回基地
Move out!
走吧
How are things going? Things okay there, Struecker?
状况如何? 没问题吧?
I don't want to talk about it now, Colonel!
我没时间谈
I'm busy.
我正在忙
Sergeant Pilla's hit!
皮中士中弹
Christ, he's fucked up!
老天 他伤得好重
Is anyone hit?
有人中弹吗?
Struecker, talk to me!
史崔克 快说
It's Sergeant Pilla!
是皮中士
What's his status?
他的状况如何?
He's dead.
他死了
Pilla's dead, sir.
皮中士死了
C- 2, this is McKnight. We have a KIA Dominick Pilla. Over.
C-2 这是麦奈 皮中士阵亡了
Roger that.
收到了
Get on that 50!
快接手五○机枪
Someone get on that 50!
快接手继续发射
It's mine.
让我来
Three guys with RPGs, coming up on your side now!
三个家伙拿着火箭筒接近你
Stay with it!
稳住!
This is 61. I'm hit. I'm hit.
我被击中了
Super 61 is hit. He is hit. Wolcott's bird is hit.
超级61号被击中 威考的直升机被击中
You want to pull those PCLs off-line or what?
快把输油阀关掉
Right, babe.
好
Come on.
撑下去啊
61, going down.
61号直升机被击中
61 going down.
61号直升机要坠毁
61 is going down.
61号直升机坠毁
Super 61 is going down.
超级61号直升机坠毁
61 is going down. I repeat, it's going down.
61号直升机坠毁 重覆 坠毁中
61's going down.
61号坠毁中
Hold on!
抓紧了
We got a Black Hawk down. We got a Black Hawk down.
有一架黑鹰直升机坠毁了
Super 61 is down. We got a bird down in the city.
超级61号直升机坠毁在市中心
Super 61 is on the deck now.
61号直升机坠毁地面
Get an MH-six on site. Check for survivors.
快赶到现场抢救生还者
Send in the SAR bird.
快派出搜救直升机
I want ground forces to move and secure a new perimeter around that crash site.
快派地面部队前往坠机地点
Can you guide the convoy in there?
你们能引导车队吗?
Roger that.
没问题
Well, move quick.
快去呀
The whole city will be coming down on top of them.
民兵会蜂拥而上围攻他们
Star 41, come inbound and see if you can land at the crash site.
请试着降落在坠机地点
Roger that. Star 41 inbound.
收到 马上去
We just lost the initiative.
我们失去了先机
25, this is 64. Over.
25 这是64部队
25. Over.
25 收到
25, Chalk Four is closest to the crash site. Over.
这是第四小队 你的小队最接近坠机地点
64, I can't see the crash site. Over.
64 我看不到坠机地点
25, it's due east of you. You will find it.
就在正东方 你一定看得到
Leave a security element in place. Take the rest of your chalk to the crash.
派人留守 率领其他人赶到坠机地点
Check for survivors. Secure the area. All other chalks will follow.
搜救生还者 维持安全 其它小队会跟着去
25, do you read me? Over.
你收到吗?
Galentine! Schmid!
杰利顿 史密斯
Get Yurek.
去找尤利
Get Twombly.
和汤比
Hey, there's a Black Hawk down.
有一架黑鹰直升机坠毁
Twombly, Nelson, stay here.
汤比和尼森留守
Hold this corner and then exfil with the humvees.
留在这儿 跟悍马车队撤退
Galentine, Schmid, you're coming with me. Let's go.
杰利顿 史医官 跟我来 走吧
How come I got to stay back here?
你为什么要我留守?
Because you're dependable.
因为你很可靠
All right...
好了
...let's go!
出发
I hate being dependable, man.
我最恨自己很可靠
Juliet 25, hostiles advancing, parallel west to your position.
你的西边有敌人接近
Women and children among them. Over.
其中有妇女小孩
Hit the wall.
靠着墙走
Incoming!
小心
Grenade!
手榴弹
Go.
快走
We still got guys inside!
里头还有弟兄
I'll go to the crash.
我要去坠机地点
You take the rest of the team. I'll finish loading the prisoners.
你带队 我继续装载人犯
No! We'll go to the crash site together.
不 我们要一起去坠机地点
Secure the perimeter, wait for the humvees.
守住防线 等待悍马车队
- Roger that. - Follow my lead.
收到 跟着我
Sarg'nt, are you receiving me?
中士 听到吗?
Yeah, I heard you. We should be leaving soon.
听到了 我们马上走
All right, we need to move out now!
好了 我们要撤退
I'll finish loading the prisoners and pick you up at the crash site!
人犯都上了车我就去接你们
Let's move out!
出发吧
Moving out! Go!
出发了 快走
Get in! Get in!
快上车
Move!
快点
Eight o'clock!
八点钟方向
Grimes, stay away from the walls.
葛姆 别靠着墙
Grimes. You okay?
你没事吧?
Yeah!
没事
Let's go, Maddox.
走吧 梅道
- C-2, convoy's moving out. - Roger that.
指挥部 车队出发了 收到
Maddox, look at these jerks! These idiots!
麦道 看看这些猪头
Go, go! Right, Maddox, right!
开快点 右转
Twombly, the convoy is leaving!
汤比 车队走了
Hey, Twombly!
嘿 汤比
What?
什么?
- I think they've forgotten us. - What?
他们忘了我们 什么?
It doesn't matter.
算了
63 confirm. Skinnies are moving in on all sides. They need help now.
敌人从四面八方赶过去 我们要赶快支援他们
Indigenous personnel advancing to Wolcott crash site.
索马利亚人往坠机地点前进
Say again. Over.
请重覆
A lot of people closing in.
一大堆人蜂拥而上
How far is Chalk Four from the crash site?
第四队离那儿有多远?
- Six blocks, sir. - They need to haul ass.
六个街口 他们要快一点
Get down! Get down!
趴下来
Scotty, are you okay?
史考帝 你没事吧?
No, don't go back!
别回去
Get down! Get down!
趴下来
Technicals!
武装车
Got them!
看到了
Six o'clock! Move, move!
六点钟方向 快走
Go, go, go!
快…快…
Go, go!
快走
Come on!
快点
Yurek, leaving!
尤利 走吧
Uniform 64, left turn. Left turn.
部队 左转
Romeo 64, I need to know before I get to the goddamn street!
你要告诉我在哪条街左转
You have to slow down. There's a delay.
先停一下 情报有延误
From the time directions are relayed from surveillance to JOC, then to me.
侦察队要先向指挥中心报告 然后再向我下令
We can't slow down! We're taking heavy enemy fire!
不能停 我们受到猛烈攻击
We can't slow down!
我们不能停下来
Danny, I'm getting information from Orion surveillance above.
我正收到侦察机的情报
So get me my fucking directions to the crash site!
快告诉我该怎么到坠机地点
Danny, hold on. I no longer have the best view of your route.
等一下 我看不到你的位置
Get your ass in the right place, goddamn it!
快到正确位置呀
What in the hell is the status of Struecker's humvees?
史崔克的车队情况如何?
Colonel Harrell, ETA to base, Struecker's column.
车队几时会回到基地?
ETA to base momentarily.
就快到了
Open the gate!
开门
- Get him out! Let's go! Let's go! - Come on.
把他抬下车 来
Watch his head.
小心头
Easy.
小心
- Blackburn, can you hear me? - Get him to a medic.
贝克朋 你听到吗? 找军医来
Star 41 is at the crash site to evacuate the injured. Over.
我们在坠机地点抢救伤者
Roger that.
收到
I got you.
我帮你
Easy.
小心
Galentine, you all right?
杰利顿 你没事吧?
Galentine, Kurth, with me! Cover fire, now.
杰利顿 寇斯 跟我来
Full cover!
掩护他们
How many are in there?
有几个人?
Two pilots are dead, two crew chiefs are wounded!
两名驾驶阵亡 两名人员受伤
- He's hurt bad. We must get out of here. - All right. Go ahead.
他伤得很重 要把他救出来 好 去吧
26, this is 25. Is that you shooting up the technicals?
这是第四小队 你在开枪吗?
This is 26. Roger that.
没错
DiTomasso, take the southeast corner. We're setting up a perimeter. Over.
狄马索 到东南边建立防线
This is 26. Roger that. Moving there now.
收到 马上赶过去
Move out!
出发
Captain Steele, come in.
史上尉 请回答
Go ahead, 25. This is 64.
请说
We got two wounded and we got both the pilots dead in the chopper!
有两名伤者 两名直升机驾驶都阵亡了
We need a medivac now!
请立刻派人接送伤兵
It's too hot to land a bird. You must secure the perimeter first. Over.
救援直升机没办法降落 你要先建立防线
Where are the humvees?
悍马车队呢?
Be advised, 25, the convoy will be there.
车队一定会到
They're encountering a lot of resistance. 64 out.
他们遭到猛烈攻击
- Get the 50 up! - You should see the crash directly ahead.
快架起机关枪 坠机地点就在前面
All I see is a roadblock!
前面只有路障
I'll have to figure out another way.
我会再找另一条路
Give me a defensive perimeter so we can load the wounded.
建立防线 把伤兵运走
Fire your weapon, Othic!
快开枪呀
Tell my girls I'll be okay.
跟我女儿说叫她们安心
Medic!
医官
Hoo-ah!
呼吓!
Medic! Medic!
医官…
Joyce! Joyce! Come on, help me pick him up!
乔斯 帮我把他抬起来
Get us off this fucking street! Where's the crash site? Say again.
快帮我们逃走 坠机地点到底在哪儿?
Keep going straight 200 meters.
直走两百米
Roger that.
收到
Let's go!
走吧
Let's go, goddamn it, let's go!
快走吧
Hey, Twombles. Come here.
汤比 过来
The humvees ain't coming back, dude.
车队不会回来了
What?
什么?
Were we supposed to go to them?
我们要去找他们吗?
I thought they were coming to us.
我以为他们要来找我们
- I think we're supposed to go to them. - Shit.
我们应该去找他们 该死
Let's go to the crash site.
我们赶去坠机地点
Okay.
好吧
Don't fire that thing so close to my head. I can barely hear as it is.
别在我耳边开枪 我听不到了
Move out.
出发
Shit! Get down!
可恶 趴下来
What did I just tell you? If you do that again...
我警告过你 别这么近
You okay? Nelson.
尼森 你没事吧?
You all right?
你没事吧?
Search and rescue bird on station inserting medics.
搜救直升机在现场进行救援
Go!
快走
Go, go!
快 快
Son of a bitch. C-2, this is 68. We've been hit.
C-2 这是68号 我被击中了
Super 68, there is smoke coming from the top of your rotor.
超级68号 你的螺旋翼冒烟
- Advise you to come out now. - Roger.
建议你立刻返航 收到
Dropping last man.
最后一个人员
Art, I've got skinnies with RPGs at 12:00. Can you see them?
我看到正前方有敌人拿着火箭筒 你看到吗?
Got them. Give me 90 degrees left.
看到了 向左转九十度
68 coming out.
我要回去了
Super 68 is out. Over.
超级68号要回基地
Hey, Wilkie, what's the situation in there?
魏肯 情况如何?
Both pilots are dead.
两名驾驶都死了
25, we can't move these guys, Matty.
我们不能移动他们
We'll kill them just carrying them.
他们会没命的
- Stabilize in here? - Roger.
就在这儿医治 收到
Stabilize in the bird. Repeat: Stabilize in here. Over.
我们要在这儿进行医治
Understood, Wilkie. We got you covered. Over.
收到 我们掩护你们
Super 64, come inbound and take Wolcott's position.
超级64号 去替代超级61号
Roger. 64 is inbound.
收到 开进中
Super 64, you all right?
超级64号 你没事吧?
This is Super 64. We're good.
这是超级64号 我没事
You sure? You look like you got clipped pretty good.
确定吗?你的机身受损
Instrument panels are okay.
仪表板一切正常
No, we're good. Got a slight vibration in the pedals, but we're good.
我们没事 机身有点晃动 不过没事
All right, put her down on the airfield, 64. Have it checked out just to be safe.
降落后进行检查以策安全
Roger.
收到
I'm getting movement in these pedals. Check the systems again.
机身晃动得很厉害 再度检查系统
We lost the tail rotor! It's gone!
尾部螺旋翼失效
64 is going down!
64号要坠机
64 is going in hard.
64要坠机了
64 going down.
我要坠机
We're going down.
我们要坠机了
Get Struecker's column back out there.
快派史崔克的车队回去
They need to get to Durant's crash site fast.
叫他们赶到杜伦的坠机地点
- Another bird down. - I want them out of there.
有另一架直升机坠毁 快去救他们
All of them.
全都救出来
Captain Steele, we got to move or we'll get pinned down!
史上尉 再不前进就会受困
We're moving as fast as we can.
我们正在尽快前进
You let me do my job and you do yours. Over.
你别管我的部队
- Fuck! Fuck! - Ruiz stay down.
哎呀 路兹 趴下来
- I fucking knew... - Medic.
我就知道 医官
Fuck this! Captain Steele, I'll take out the threat in the window.
去他的! 史上尉 我来对付狙击手
We'll rally at the gray building. Coming through.
我们到灰色大楼集合
Sarg'nt!
中士
All right, let's move!
好 走吧
Cover me!
掩护我
- Let's go, let's move! - Moving out.
快走吧 快走
Friendly!
友军
Friendlies coming through!
我是友军
Let's go, let's go! Move up!
走吧 快走
Come on, come on!
快…
Move up! Go! Move up!
快走…快…
What the fuck are you doing out there?
你在干什么?
Doing my job! We got to get to that crash site!
我们要赶到坠机地点
We got to get on that street, and we got to move!
我们一定要赶到那条街
And you have got to keep up, sir!
你也要跟上来
Don't you ever give me orders, Sergeant.
别对我下令 中士
We are combat ineffective, understand?
我们没办法迎敌
We got too many wounded to move!
太多伤兵了
Then give me some shooters and I'll circle us to the bird.
让我带人手绕到坠机地点
Grimes! You're with Chalk Four?
葛姆 你在第四小队吗?
Yes, sir!
是的 长官
All right, hook up with Delta! Rejoin with Sergeant Eversmann.
去跟反恐怖部队和艾中士会合
The rest of you, secure this position!
其他的人留守这里
Treat the wounded, we'll wait for the convoy!
照顾伤兵 等待车队
Then we'll rally at the crash site. Roger!
然后在坠机地点会合
My guys, let's go!
我的手下跟我走
C- 2, I have two Delta snipers, Shughart and Gordon...
两名反恐怖部队狙击手 舒哈和葛顿
...volunteering to secure crash site two. Over.
自愿前往第二坠机地点
No, Super 62, negative that request. Can't risk another bird.
不准 不能再牺牲另一架直升机
We don't see anything moving down there, we don't even know if anyone's alive.
我们不能确定有人生还
A ground team is being organized to go in now.
地面部队正在赶去
ETA on ground team? Over.
多久能赶到?
Unknown, not long.
不知道 不久吧
Do what you can from the air.
你们尽力从空中协助
All right, gather around!
大家过来
Durant's 64 is down. We're going back in to get him!
杜伦坠毁了 我们要去救他
That's crazy. Is there anyone alive?
你疯了 有人生还吗?
Doesn't matter, no one gets left behind.
无所谓 绝不能抛弃同胞
We're wasting time here.
这是浪费时间
Refit and max out ammo and grenades, you got five!
五分钟内重新整理弹药
Sizemore, where are you going?
塞斯莫 你想去哪儿?
- With you guys. - Not with that cast on you're not.
跟你们一起走 你受了伤不能去
All right, all right, all right. Go get your k-pot.
好吧 去拿头盔吧
Talk to me.
说话呀
I can't go back out there.
我不能再回去
Thomas, everyone feels the same way you do. All right?
汤玛斯 大家都很害怕
It's what you do right now that makes a difference.
你现在的表现才重要
It's your call.
这是你的决定
Hoo-ah?
呼吓?
Hoo-ah.
呼吓
It'll probably help to wash the blood out of the humvees.
最好把悍马车上的血迹冲掉
Sergeant Struecker!
史崔克中士
Sergeant Struecker! Can I go, Sarge?
我能去吗?
- You got some ammo? - Roger, Sarge!
你有弹药吗? 有
Hop in!
上来吧
Wait!
等等
Let's go, Thomas. Get in!
来吧 上车
Which way?
走哪儿?
- That way, I think! - Not so fucking loud.
那儿吧 别这么大声
Nice donkey.
乖驴子
Rangers?
游骑兵吗?
Who?
你是谁?
It's Yurek! You fucking assholes!
我是尤利啦 猪头
Fuck!
靠
Dude, we almost fucking killed you!
我们差点杀死你
- Come to us! - Fuck you, come to me.
你过来 靠 你们过来
Sorry, Sarge!
对不起 中士
Dude, where the fuck have you been?
你上哪儿了?
Never mind, you brought NOD, right?
你带了夜视镜吗?
No, I didn't and you want to know why?
没有 你知道原因吗?
Because you said: "You won't need that, we'll be back in a half-hour."
因为你说半小时就能回基地
Well, I wasn't saying it to you.
我不是跟你说的
Nelson, cover this way.
尼森 过来
We'll need night vision.
我们需要夜视镜
What's the matter with you?
你在等什么?
Oh, he's deaf. It's my fault.
他聋了 都是我害的
- We need to get out of here! - That way.
我们一定要走 那儿
We can't be far from the crash. Which way?
离坠机地点不远了 在哪儿?
I thought you might know.
我以为你知道
Let's move out.
出发吧
Nelson, Twombly? Come in. Over.
尼森 汤比 请回答
Nelson, Twombly, this is Galentine. We need a position of the convoy. Over.
这是杰利顿 车队的位置在哪里?
I can't raise them, Sergeant.
我联络不到他们
Sir, let's get the fuck out of here and evac!
我们快撤退吧
- Let's move out. - Back to the stronghold!
快走吧 快回到据点
Come on!
走吧
Ground forces have occupied several buildings along Marehan Road...
地面部队占领几栋建筑物
...but they're all spread out.
但是都分散开来
Eversmann's Chalk Four has set up a perimeter around Wolcott's crash site.
艾中士的第四小队 在威考的坠机地点建立防线
DiTomasso is in the adjacent structure.
狄马索在隔壁的大楼
Captain Steele and about 40 men, Rangers, are here, a couple blocks away.
史上尉的游骑兵队员在这儿 两个街口外
They're banged up pretty bad.
他们的情况很惨
He set up a casualty collection point, I don't think they'll be able to move.
他设立了死伤聚集点 没办法前进
Sergeant Sanderson and a small Delta team...
桑德森中士率领手下
...are moving from Steele's position to the crash site as we speak.
正在赶往坠机地点
Draw off fire!
把炮火引开
When this asshole stops to reload, cover me!
等对方装子弹就掩护我
- Go! - Sir.
快 长官
Again!
再来
Loading!
掩护我
Keep going!
继续
I'm jammed!
卡住了
I got it!
让我来
No, shit!
该死
RPG!
火箭弹
You all right? You okay?
你没事吧?
Yeah. I can hear bells ringing.
没事 我死不了
Come on! Come on!
快 来吧
Go!
走吧
A crowd is advancing six, seven blocks from the crash.
有一群人正走向坠机地点
Shughart and Gordon again request permission...
舒哈和葛顿再度请求
...to secure until convoy arrives. Over.
前往坠机地点进行救援
General, crowds are in the hundreds now.
人群增加到好几百人
From where they are, they can see things clearer than any of us.
他们看得会比我们清楚
They know what they're asking.
他们很清楚状况
Let me talk to them.
让我跟他们说
This is Garrison.
这是盖将军
I want to make sure that you understand what you're asking, so say it out loud.
我要确定你们很清楚状况 大声地说出来
We're asking to go in and set up a perimeter until ground support arrives.
我们要求在坠机地点建立防线
You realize that I cannot tell you when that might be, it could take a while.
支援部队没那么快赶到
- Roger that. - You still want to go in there?
我知道 你们还是要去?
Yes, sir.
是 长官
- Colonel Harrell? - Yes, General?
哈中校 是 将军
It's your call.
这是你的决定
Roger that.
收到
Goffena, put them in.
把他们送过去
Motherfucker. Motherfucker.
该死 该死
RPG!
火箭弹
Set up your perimeter!
建立防线
There's a fucking rocket in him, sir!
他身上有火箭弹
Othic, calm down, goddamn it! There's live ordnance, now get out!
冷静点 它会爆炸 快走
Son of a bitch.
可恶
All right, lift him up! Lift him up! Easy, easy!
把他抬起来 小心点
All right, get him in there! Good, good! Easy, easy!
把他抬上车 很好
Get in that truck and drive.
快上车 开车
- But I'm shot, Colonel. - Everybody's shot.
我受伤了 大家都受伤了
We need the prisoners! Let's go!
把人犯送回去
Surveillance says to take Hawlwadig, then go straight.
你要开到哈瓦迪街直走
McKnight, we need you to turn around and head back to Hawlwadig.
我要你回头开到哈瓦迪街
You're shitting me! We just came through there!
拜托 我们才从那儿来
There must be a better route!
一定有更好的路线
That's the info I'm getting from JOC, you need to turn around and head back.
这是指挥中心的情报 你要调头回去
Roger that. Roger that.
收到了
I cannot believe this shit! Turn us around, Maddox.
我不敢相信 快调头
They're trying to get us fucking killed!
他们会把我们害死
Just get it over with! Drive!
快开车吧
Goddamn!
该死
Get us out of here, goddamn it, drive!
快走吧 开车
Keep your foot on the gas!
快踩油门
Fuck!
去死
Shit.
该死
C- 2, Shughart and Gordon are on the deck. Over.
舒哈和葛顿下去了
Roger.
收到
Friendlies!
是友军!别开枪
God, it's good to see you!
天啊 见到你真好
It's good to see you. How bad?
你也是 你伤得多重?
My leg's broken and my back feels kind of weird.
我的腿断了 我的背很痛
We've got to get you out of here.
我们要把你救出去
I'm pulling him out! Cover!
我把他拉出来
Wait, I...
等等
I'm putting you down.
我把你放下来
C-2, we're at the 64 crash site, securing perimeter.
我们在坠机地点建立防线
- You all right? - Yeah, I'm good.
你还好吧? 我还好
You're locked and loaded.
枪上膛了
Any skinnies come around these corners, you watch our backs.
后面有敌人就帮我们解决掉
- Where's the rescue squad? - We're it.
救援部队呢? 我们就是了
All right, stop, stop, Maddox. Stop.
好了 停车
Son of a bitch.
可恶
Romeo 64, we're back where we started.
我们又回到原点
I'm low on ammo, I got many wounded including me...
弹药快用完了 大家都受伤
...vehicles that are barely running.
车辆几乎毁损
Okay, Danny, I need a no-b.s. Assessment here.
好了 你就老实说吧
Can you get to the crash site?
你能到坠机地点吗?
Colonel, I can't see shit.
我什么也看不到
Negative.
不能
With the amount of wounded we have, we'd do more harm than good.
伤兵太多 我们去也没用
We need to come back to base, rearm and regroup and then we can go back out.
我们要回基地补充弹药 然后再回来
Roger.
收到
C-2, bring them back. Get them out of there.
把他们叫回来 叫他们快走
Roger. Return to base.
收到 回基地吧
We're going home!
我们要回去了
Let's go. Left.
走吧 左转
Roger that. Understand. Convoy returning to base.
收到了 车队要回基地
- What's up? - They're sending them back.
怎么回事? 车队被叫回去了
The convoy's headed back to base camp.
车队要回基地
Oh, now that makes sense, don't it?
这太妙了
We need to exfil the wounded now and get out of here before it's too late!
我们要赶紧把伤兵送回去
If Colonel McKnight went back to base, then he had a good reason.
麦中校要回基地一定有理由
It changes nothing.
我们的任务不变
All right, listen up.
大伙儿听好
We're going to hold the perimeter and we're going to hold the strongpoint.
我们要守住这个据点
Conserve your ammo. Only shoot at what you can hit.
保留弹药 有必要才开枪
The convoy is going to come.
车队一定会回来
We're going to get home.
我们一定能回家
Loading!
掩护我
Randy, I need a pistol mag!
蓝迪 我要弹匣
Randy, last mag!
最后一个弹匣
Gordy!
葛顿
Fuck!
该死
Gordy is gone, man. I'll be outside.
葛顿死了 我出去拼了
Good luck.
祝好运
We need the 10th Mountain in there. Everything they got.
快向第十山地师求救
Pakistanis, Malays, I want their tanks and APCs.
巴基斯坦军队 马来西亚军队 我要他们的坦克车和装甲车
They don't know we've gone in.
他们不知道我们的行动
We have stirred up a hornet's nest here. We're fighting the entire city.
我们捅出了大篓子 整个城市都在攻击我们
I want every vehicle possible that's got 4 wheels and armor. Get everything.
我要每一辆军事车辆的支援 快去找 快去
Once they've assembled, we'll move our men out of the hostile area...
我要他们我们的弟兄救出敌区
...and back to the Pakistani Stadium, the safe zone.
安全送到巴基斯坦军队的基地
- Now, let's go. - Roger that.
快去吧 遵命 长官
Mohamed Farrah Aidid...
穆罕默德艾迪德
claims this prisoner...
要活捉
... alive!
这名战俘
On your knees! Get down! Get down!
跪下来 快点
Stay with me. You just got a bullet in the leg.
撑着点 你只是大腿中弹
See where those tires are burning? All that black smoke?
你看到烧轮胎的黑烟吗?
Roger. I can see it, but I can't get there. Over.
我看到了 但我到不了那儿
Go 100 meters past it. That's the crash.
坠机地点离那儿只有一百米
Negative. You don't understand.
你不明白
It's roadblock after roadblock. You have to find us another route. Over.
前面都是路障 要找另一条路
There ain't one. The only other route is all the way around the city.
另一条路要绕过整座城市
Roger that.
收到
Kilo 64, this is Kilo 11.
凯罗64号 这是凯罗11号
Request permission to move to crash site number two on foot. Over.
请准许我步行到坠机地点
Green light, Kilo 11.
好的 凯罗11号
Stop the vehicle. Let me out.
停车 让我下去
After I'm finished with this, I'll whip you boys up some margaritas.
回去我要好好请你们喝一杯
The usual. Blended, no salt.
玛格丽特调酒 不加盐
This is Kilo 12. We've got to change our position. Over.
这是凯罗12号 我们一定要移动位置
Eversmann, come in.
艾中士 请回答
Eversmann.
艾中士
- Roger who is this? - Sanderson.
收到 你是谁? 桑中士
Do not... I say again, do not fire to the east. We are coming to you.
千万别向东边开枪 我们要过去
Understood.
了解
DiTomasso and his men are on the southeast corner.
狄马索在东南角
We need you on the northeast building.
你们要占领东北角
Roger. We'll take it.
收到 没问题
Watch out for skinnies. They're on the rooftops.
小心敌人 他们在屋顶
They're in prayer but not for much longer.
他们的祷告就快结束了
Hold your fire to the east.
别向东边开火
Eversmann? It's Yurek.
艾中士 这是尤利
I got Nelson and Twombly with me.
尼森和汤比跟我在一起
We got the chopper in sight. Where are you?
我们看到直升机 你在哪里?
We're on the southwest corner. Where have you been? Are you okay?
我们在西南角 你没事吧?
Yeah.
没事
Hold your fire. We're coming in.
别开枪 我们来了
We got to go.
我们要走了
Shawn, listen! Sergeant Yurek's going to run first.
听好 尤中士要先跑
When he gets across the street, he'll turn around and cover you as you run.
等他过了马路 就会转过头掩护你
Listen closely. When you get there, you'll turn around and cover me, okay?
听清楚了 你到了那儿也要掩护我
You won't just run to Eversmann's position.
你不能直接跑去找艾中士
You're going to stop and you are going to cover me.
你要停下来掩护我
It's important you understand that.
你一定要搞清楚这点
Okay, you ready?
好了吗?
Yeah, I guess.
好了
- Don't forget. - What?
别忘了 什么?
Don't forget.
别忘了我
I got them in my sight, Sarg'nt. They're coming up on the west gate.
我看到他们了 他们来了
I see them.
我看到了
Let's move out.
出去吧
Can you cover us, Sergeant?
你能掩护我们吗?
We got you.
没问题
Nelson!
尼森
Fuck!
可恶
Twombly!
汤比
Smith! No!
史密斯 不!
You all right?
你没事吧?
Get it off of me!
快弄掉 快点
Get it off!
快呀
Come on, man. Come on.
快
Doc! Need some help with Smith here!
医官 快来帮史密斯
My leg! My leg!
我的腿
Come on, Jamie, I got you!
我帮你
Up, one, two, three.
抬起来 1 2 3
- You're all right. - I need some pressure on this wound.
你没事了 用力压他的伤口
My right thigh!
我的右腿
Pressure, yeah.
用力压
- Are my balls okay? - You still have your balls.
我的蛋蛋还在吧? 还在啦
I need more men in here.
我需要帮手
Twombly! Nelson!
汤比 尼森
- Put him down. - Oh, man, that really...
压住他 真是...
- It really hurts! - Direct pressure on that.
真是很痛 直接施加压力
It's okay, it's okay.
没事的
- Let me see it! - All right.
让我看 好了
All right, let me get a look at that.
让我看看
Oh, shit!
该死
- What the fuck was that? - It's all right.
怎么回事? 没事
Hold that down. I need a medivac now.
按住 我要立刻送他回去
Fuck. Galentine!
杰利顿
It's all right.
没事
Galentine! Get me Captain Steele!
杰利顿 快帮我接史上尉
- Sarg'nt Ruiz, how you doing? - Juliet 64, come in. Over.
你还好吧? 请回答
They're not going to come and get us. They're not going to come for us.
他们不会来接我们了
I need you to suck it up, Sarg'nt. I need you to focus.
给我闭嘴 振作点
- Can you do that? - Juliet 64, come in. Over.
你办得到吗? 请回答
Now, can you hold your weapon?
你能开枪吗?
Yes, sir.
能
Anybody comes through that door gets two in the chest and one in the head.
谁敢闯进来就让他吃子弹
- You understand? - I'm still in the fight, sir.
明白吗? 我可以打仗
Captain Steele, I need a medivac in here now!
史上尉 请派人接送伤兵
- Corporal Smith has been hit! - Hold on, 25.
史下士中弹 等一下
Still in the fight.
我可以打仗
He's hurt pretty bad.
他伤得很重
25, we got wounded too. You'll have to maintain your situation, over.
我们也有伤兵 你要留在原地
If he doesn't get help in a half-hour, he's in trouble!
他再不进医院就会没命
C- 2, this is 64.
C-2 这是部队
Requesting a medivac for a critically wounded at Chalk Four's location. Over.
第四小队需要医疗救援
Command, Chalk Four is requesting medivac.
第四小队请求医疗救援
Can't risk it. It's still too hot.
战况激烈 不能冒险
Captain, we cannot send in medivac at this time. Sit tight. Over.
我们不能派出医疗救援 撑下去
25, this is 64. Negative on the medivac. It's not possible.
25号 这是64号  没有医疗救援 战况太激烈
JOC cannot risk another bird. You'll just have to hold on.
不能再冒险派救援直升机 你们要撑下去
All right. I got him.
让我来
I want direct pressure on the wound.
直接压在伤口上
It's going to be all right.
你不会有事的
I think this is mine!
这是我的直升机
This is Kilo 11. I'm at the Durant crash site.
这是凯罗11号  我到了杜伦的坠机地点
Roger that.
收到
Crash site two secured.
第二坠机地点安全
Lieutenant Colonel Cribbs for you, sir.
柯中校找你
Cribbs?
柯中校?
- They're still debating the route. - How long?
他们还在讨论路线 还要多久?
At least a couple of hours.
至少两个小时
We haven't got that long, Joe.
来不及了
Pakistani General says, since we didn't deign to inform him of the raid...
巴基斯坦将军说 我们事先没有通知他们
...it'll take some time to mobilize the 10th Mountain and 100 vehicles.
动员第十山地师要花点时间
You tell the general this:
你告诉他
I understand, but it is my duty to remind him...
我了解 但是我也要提醒他
...that my men are surrounded by thousands of armed Somali militia.
我的手下被武装民兵团团包围
It's imperative that we move them out of the hostile area and into the safe zone.
我们必须立刻把他们救出敌区
I need his help now.
我需要他的帮助
Yes, sir.
是 长官
Durant.
杜伦
Michael Durant.
迈可杜伦
Yes.
是的
You are the Ranger who kills my people?
你是杀我同胞的游骑兵队员?
I'm not a Ranger. I'm a pilot.
我不是 我是驾驶员
That's right.
没错
None of you Americans smoke anymore.
美国人不抽烟了
You all live long, dull, uninteresting lives.
你们都过着无趣的生活
What do you want with me?
你为什么要抓我?
You have taken hostages.
你们手上有我们的人质
We have you.
我们手上有你
My government will never negotiate for me.
美国政府才不会跟你谈判
Then perhaps you and I can negotiate, huh?
那么我就跟你谈判吧
Soldier to soldier.
我们都是军人
I'm not in charge.
我不是指挥官
Course not. You have the power to kill, but not negotiate.
当然不是 你们能杀人却不能谈判
In Somalia, killing is negotiation.
在索马利亚 杀人就是谈判
Do you really think if you get General Aidid...
你们真的以为抓到艾迪德将军
...we will simply put down our weapons...
我们就会放下武器
...and adopt American democracy?
接受美式民主
That the killing will stop?
或是停止杀戮吗?
We know this: Without victory, there can be no peace.
我只知道没有胜利就没有和平
There will always be killing, you see?
杀戮永远不会停止
This is how things are in our world.
这就是我们的方法 迈可杜伦 我们不会抛弃你
Mike Durant, we won't leave you behind.
迈可杜伦 我们不会抛弃你
You got to take over from me. Both hands.
换你来 用双手按住
It's the femoral artery, but I can't see it.
伤口在股动脉 但是我看不到
Which means that it's retracted up into the pelvis.
它一定缩进骨盆
I have to find it and clamp it. It's the only way to stop the bleeding.
我必须把它夹住 这样才能止血
I got no more IVs.
麻醉剂用完了
So, I'm going to need you to assist. Okay?
所以我要你帮忙 好吗?
Yeah, yeah.
好
Now listen, Jamie. I got to do something, it's going to hurt.
听好 我要做一件事
I got to cause you more pain, but I have to do it to help you.
你会很痛 不过我必须帮助你
All right, you understand?
你懂吗?
- Morphine. - I can't.
吗啡 不行
It'll lower your heart rate too far. I'm sorry.
那会降低你的心跳
Twombly, why don't you take his hands?
汤比 抓住他的手
Hold the wound open, keep pressure on the top of the leg.
把伤口撑开 压住他的大腿
Yurek, take the feet and a flashlight.
尤利 帮我拿手电筒
On my count.
我数到三
All right, Jamie. All right.
准备好了
1 2 One. Two.
1 2
Wait, wait. Okay. I feel it.
等等 摸到了
I feel the pulse.
我摸到脉搏
I got it. I got it.
我找到了
I got it, yeah. I got it.
找到了…
- I got it. - You got it?
找到了? 找到了
Clamp?
夹子
I got it clamped.
钳住了
- Hold it. - Got it.
拿住 好
Here, grab it.
这里 抓住
- It's tearing. - I got it.
它破了 我抓住了
- Doc, it's going back in! - Hold it!
它又缩回去了 抓住它
It's tearing!
破了
- Okay. Get out. Hold the wound. - Okay, I'm holding.
出来 撑开伤口 撑开了
Move your hand.
把手拿开
What?
怎么了?
Fix it?
治好了吗?
Yeah, yeah. We got it.
对 治好了
What the hell are you doing?
你在干什么?
It's all in the grind, Sarg'nt. Can't be too fine, can't be too coarse.
关键是磨咖啡豆 不能磨得太细或太粗
Grimesy, you are squared away.
葛姆 你都弄好了
Sarg'nt, how would you like a nice hot cup of Joe?
来一杯热腾腾的咖啡吧
Gold Coast blend.
黄金海岸口味
Sit down. I want to take a look at that foot.
坐下来 我看你的伤口
- No, it's not a problem. - Come on.
这不算什么 来
- Where the hell did they find you? - Behind a desk.
他们从哪儿把你找来? 办公桌后面
No, really. What, you think I'm kidding?
是真的 我没开玩笑
- Is anybody hit? - We're good!
有人受伤吗? 没有
You all right?
你们没事吧?
Yeah!
没事
Is everybody all right?
大家都没事吧?
Incoming!
火箭弹
Keep firing... faster!
继续开火 快点
DiTomasso's hit! Pull him out!
狄马索中弹 快救他
Ranger here. This is Kilo 11.
这是凯罗11号
Chalk Four. We're at the southeast corner of the crash. Who's this?
我们在东南角 你是谁?
This is Hoot. I'm coming with three friendlies.
胡特 我带了三名同胞来
I need cover fire. Over.
请掩护我
Roger, Kilo 11. Hold your fire! Deltas coming in.
收到 凯罗11号 停火 反恐怖部队来了
Hold your fire! Hold your fire!
停火
Ground personnel will have to mark target positions with infrared strobes.
地面部队要用红外线求生灯做记号
Get little birds on strafing runs and keep them going all night long.
派出攻击直升机向敌人扫射
If we don't hold back this city...
如果控制不了状况
...we'll have a 100 caskets to fill by morning.
我们的死伤会很惨重
Yes, sir.
是 长官
Colonel Harrell, ground personnel at crash site one...
第一坠机地点的地面部队
... will have to mark the target with infrared strobes to prep for air strike.
要用红外线求生灯在目标上做记号
McKnight.
麦中校
Between the 10th Mountain and U.N., we got enough personnel, okay?
第十山地师的支援部队就够了
Danny, you guys do not have to go back out again.
你们不必再回去
I can't die here, man.
我不能死在这儿
You're not going to die, all right? You're not going to die.
你不会死的 你不会死
I'm sorry.
对不起
You don't have anything to be sorry for.
你不必道歉
You saved Twombly. You did perfect.
你救了汤比 你干得很好
You okay, Twombs?
汤比 你没事吧?
Yeah, I'm okay, Jamie.
我没事
You did what you were trained to do.
你是个好军人
You should be proud of that.
你应该感到自傲
Be proud of that.
你要感到骄傲
- Ev? - Yeah.
小艾 什么事?
Do me a favor.
帮我一个忙
You tell my parents that I fought well today.
跟我父母说我今天很英勇
And that I fought hard.
我也尽了全力
You're going to tell them yourself, okay?
你要亲口跟他们说
Do you hear me?
听到吗?
All right?
好吗?
- Are the humvees here? - They're coming, Jamie.
悍马车队来了吗? 他们来了
They're coming.
来了
You just got to hang in there a little bit.
你要撑下去
- You hold on for just a little bit. - I can.
再多撑一下子 小意思
I can.
我行的
It's nothing.
没问题…
- It's nothing. - It's nothing.
没问题 没问题
Oh, shit.
可恶
Hold the wound.
压住伤口
Doc.
医官
It's okay.
没事
What are you doing?
你在干嘛?
We need the ammo.
我们需要弹药
You did all you could here.
你已经尽了力
They should've sent a medivac.
他们应该派直升机救援
Right now we'd be out there defending another crashed chopper.
它一定会被击落
More men would get torn up.
更多人会受伤
Maybe.
也许吧
See, you're thinking. Don't.
别想那么多
Because, Sergeant, you can't control who gets hit or who doesn't.
你不能决定谁受伤
Who falls out of a chopper or why.
或是谁从直升机上摔落
It ain't up to you. It's just war.
这是战争 你也无能为力
Yeah, well, Smith's still dead.
史密斯还是死了
- This all happened because Blackburn fell. - Should have, could have, don't matter.
都是因为贝克朋摔下来 你想这么多也没用
You'll get plenty of time to think about all that later. Believe me.
以后你有的是时间去想
Sergeant, you got your men this far.
你把弟兄们带到这儿
You did it right today.
你已经尽了全力
You need to start thinking about getting these men out of here.
你要想该怎么把他们救出去
Well, shall we?
走吧
I need four guys in this corner now!
我要四个人守住这角落
RPG!
火箭弹
This is Barber 52 in position for gun run.
我准备进行机关枪扫射
Jesus Christ. Look at that.
老天爷 你看看
This is 25! I can see you. You're right above me.
我看到了 你就在我上方
Eversmann, I can't tell who's who down there. Too much activity.
我分不出谁是敌谁是友 状况太混乱了
I'll mark the target with a strobe! Over.
我会用红外线求生灯做记号
Roger that.
收到
You see it?
看到吗?
Nah, I can't see shit.
我什么也看不到
- I'm putting it on the roof. - You're going to need help!
我要丢到屋顶 你需要帮忙
Cover me.
掩护我
Okay, guys, we're going to lay down some cover fire for him on three!
我数到三就开枪掩护他
Ready?
好了吗?
Three. Go!
3 开枪
I got your position. I got the target. We're inbound and hot.
我看到目标了 准备进行扫射
C- 2, miniguns dry. Request permission to return to base. Rearm. Over.
C-2 弹药用完了 请求返回基地
Roger that. Second team inbound. Your station.
收到 第二队前往支援
On your location, four minutes.
四分钟后抵达
All right, they're here. Get the wounded ready to move.
车队来了 准备走了
Lay down some cover fire!
掩护我们
I thought I heard a noise out here!
我早就听到你们了
- Load up. We're getting out of here. - Yes, sir.
准备好 我们要出发 是 长官
25, this is 64. The rescue column's here and will be with you in about 5 minutes.
25号 这是64号  救援车队出发了五分钟后抵达
Prepare your men for exfil.
准备撤退
Yeah, roger that, sir! Roger that!
收到 收到了
Five minutes! The convoy is going to be here in five minutes!
救援车队五分钟后就到
I need a mag! Eversmann, I'm out!
我要弹匣 我用完了
My last one!
最后一个
The convoy is here!
救援车队来了
Sergeant Eversmann. I heard you guys needed a lift!
艾中士 听说你们要搭便车
Yes, sir!
是的 长官
Bring your wounded and start loading them up!
把伤兵抬上来
Hey, I got you. I got you.
我扶你
It's okay. I want to walk.
没关系 我想用走的
Yeah, I would too. Let's go!
我也一样 走吧
Move!
出发
We get the pilots' bodies out, and then we go to the stadium.
找到驾驶尸体就回体育场
We're running out of room around here.
车上没有地方了
Cram into every possible space.
尽量挤一挤
Okay, 10th Mountain provides security for armor, walks us out of the hot zone.
第十山地师出动装甲车 保护我们从敌区撤退
10th Mountain? No.
第十山地师?
Sir, with respect, my Rangers can provide rear security.
我们游骑兵的人可以殿后
We'll walk you out of the hot zone, then we'll jump on the last few vehicles.
我们走出敌区然后再坐车
Okay, let's get out of here.
好 出发吧
Let's go.
走吧
- All right, you got him? - Yeah, come on.
好了吗? 来吧
Come on!
来
These things are fucking bullet magnets. Come on, let's go!
目标太明显了 快走吧
We go when I'm ordered to, soldier.
我要接到命令才能走
Careful.
小心点
Easy. Go easy.
小心
Colonel, what is going on down there?
上校 怎么回事?
They're dismantling the entire cockpit around the body.
他们绕着尸体拆解驾驶舱
How long is it going to take? I need an honest, no-shit assessment.
还要多久?我要你老实说
They can't say!
说不准
Danny...
丹尼
...no one gets left behind.
绝对不能抛弃同胞
You understand me, son?
你明白吗?
Yes, General.
明白
Do what you have to do.
你要尽一切可能
Roger.
遵命
- Come on. Bring him through. - I got him.
快点 把他抬出来 好了
- Get all his gear. Get the wounded out. - Got you, sir!
把伤兵救出来 遵命
- Move! - Got you!
快走 好
Move out! Move out! Let's go!
快走
Fuck!
该死
Fire in the hole!
要爆炸了
- Let's go! Move! - Let's go!
快走 走吧
- Open the hatch! We got men back here! - No room here! Go on the roof!
快开门 我们要上去 挤不下了 坐到车顶
What's going on?
怎么回事?
- The roof? - I'm not getting on no fucking roof!
车顶? 我才不坐车顶
No, no, it's full.
没地方坐了
We're running out. Keep moving. Use the vehicles as cover.
前进吧 用装甲车当掩护
Move it! Let's go!
走吧
All right, hold it up. Hold it up.
等一下
- Move! - Go! Move!
出发吧 走
Go!
走
Get down! Get down!
趴下来
Get down, lady!
让开
I'm out of ammo!
我没子弹了
Sanderson, I'm out of ammo!
桑德森 我没子弹了
Don't you do it.
别拿枪
- What are you doing? - Don't you damn do it.
你在干嘛? 别开枪
Kurth, let's go!
走吧
Easy.
小心点
Ah, shit.
可恶
Bullet missed your jugular by about three millimeters. Don't move.
子弹错过你的颈静脉 别动
Hurry up, hurry up.
快点啦
Little short on coffee, but I got you some tea.
咖啡没了 我替你倒了茶
How you doing, soldier?
你还好吧?
Can't feel a thing.
我没有感觉
Take his pulse.
替他量脉搏
Hey, Sarg'nt.
中士
Captain.
队长
Lorenzo. How you doing?
你还好吧?
It went in and out, so the medic said I should be okay in a couple of days.
子弹穿过去 医官说我过两天就没事
That's great news.
真是好消息
Are we going after them?
我们要继续打吗?
You bet your ass we will. We got to regroup.
当然了 我们要重新整队
Don't go out there without me.
别把我留下来
Don't go back out there without me.
别丢下我就回去
I can still do my job.
我还能打仗
You get some rest now, okay?
好好休息吧
You're going back in?
你要回去?
There are still men out there.
战区还有弟兄
Goddamn.
该死
When I go home...
我每次回家
...and people ask me:
他们都问我
"Hey, Hoot, why do you do it, man?
胡特 你为什么从军?
"Why? You some kind of war junkie?"
难道你是打仗打上瘾吗?
I won't say a goddamn word.
我一句话也不说
Why?
为什么?
They won't understand.
他们不会懂
They won't understand why we do it.
他们不懂我们干嘛打仗
They won't understand it's about the men next to you.
我们是为了同胞弟兄拼命
And that's it.
就这么简单
That's all it is.
很简单
Don't even think about it, all right? I'm better on my own.
想都别想 我习惯单枪匹马
We started a whole new week. It's Monday.
星期一 又是一周的开始
I was talking to Blackburn the other day...
贝克朋问我
... and he asked me, "What changed? Why are we going home?"
什么改变了? 我们为什么要回家?
And I said, "Nothing."
我说什么都没变
But that's not true, you know. I think everything's changed.
但这不是实话 一切都变了
I know I've changed.
我也变了
A friend of mine asked me before I got here...
之前有一个朋友问我
It was when we were all shipping out.
那是在我们被派来之前
He asked me:
他问我
"Why are you going to fight somebody else's war?
你为什么要去打别人的仗?
"What, do y'all think you're heroes?"
你自以为是英雄吗?
I didn't know what to say at the time...
当时我不知道该说什么
...but if he asked me again, I'd say no.
现在我的答案是不
I'd say there's no way in hell.
我不想当英雄
Nobody asks to be a hero.
没有人想当英雄
It just sometimes turns out that way.
只是有时候时势造英雄
I'll talk to your ma and pa when I get home, okay?
我会去找你的父母
My love, you are strong and you will do well in life.
我的爱 你会坚强地活下去
I love you and my children deeply.
我爱你和我的孩子
Today and tomorrow, let each day grow and grow.
每一天都会成长茁壮
Keep smiling and never give up, even when things get you down.
保持笑容 千万别被困境打倒
So, in closing, my love...
最后 我的爱
... tonight, tuck my children in bed warmly.
今晚替我哄我的孩子入睡
Tell them I love them. Then hug them for me...
跟他们说我爱他们... 替我抱抱他们
... and give them both a kiss good night for Daddy.
替爸爸亲吻他们道晚安